Melissa McFadzien

mmcf647@aucklanduni.ac.nz linkedin.com/in/melissa-mcfadzien 021 179 8602

Summary

Current Master of Information Technology student at the University of Auckland.

After studying Communication Design as an undergraduate, I worked in various roles within the fashion retail and E-commerce sector, gaining experience in customer service, operations, and digital marketing / content creation.

The challenges and problem-solving opportunities generated by the Covid-19 pandemic led me to discover my passion for tech-based solutions and coding, which I am now pursuing full time as a master's student.

Skills

- Java - HTML - UX / UI Design

- JavaScript - CSS - Adobe Creative Suite (Ps, Id, Ai)

React JS - SQL - Creative problem solving

- Vue JS - Git - Peer tutoring

Experience

The University of Auckland Auckland, NZ

Oct 22 - present

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Tutoring students in the Post Graduate Certificate of Information Technology. Responsibilities include providing support during lab exercises for Java programming and web development (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript), monitoring group project progress and doing live demonstrations of solutions for class and lab activities.

Pagani Clothing Ltd. Auckland, NZ

2018 - 2021

Digital Content Producer June 2020 - August 2021

Producing and managing all digital and visual content, including design and production of digital communications, website asset and product management, and directing / photographing product and campaign imagery.

Digital Marketing Assistant March 2019 - June 2020

Assisting in all areas of the marketing and web store teams. Responsibilities included website maintenance, budget and sales reporting, third-party marketing correspondence, and office culture coordination.

Product Survey and Web Dispatch Support November 2018 - March 2019

Creating, sending, and reporting daily product response surveys used for purchasing and budgeting. During this time, I also supported the web dispatch team, picking and packing orders.

2018

Back of House Operations Coordinator May 2018 - October 2018

Back of House Operations Coordinator for a renowned multi-brand luxury boutique, with 5 stores across Brooklyn and Los Angeles. Responsibilities included multi-store stock management and transfers, international vendor communications and special-order management.

Sales Associate January 2018 - May 2018

SNOWE Home New York, NY

Oct - Dec 2017

Sales Associate and Brand Ambassador

I was part of the team opening the first pop-up store for the high-profile homeware start-up Snowe in bustling central SoHo. Responsibilities included introducing the brand to customers, hosting launch events and coordinating store operations.

Education

2023

The University of Auckland

Master's Degree - Information Technology

2016

Auckland University of Technology

Bachelor's Degree - Communication Design (formerly Graphic Design)

- Major in Illustration and Photography
- Minor in Creative Entrepreneurship

Other

- Programming with C# Code Like a Girl
- Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp

Honours and Awards

- Elected Student Representative on the Auckland ICT Graduate School Board of Studies 2023
- First in Course Award in INFOSYS 727 Semester Two, 2022
- Certificate of Outstanding Achievement in COMPSCI 719 Semester One, 2022

References available on request.